Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
Episode 35
الحلقة 35
Yuzhen Pavilion
جناح يوجين
Young Master Mei Si.
السيد الشاب مي سي.
Why do you like me?
لماذا تحبني؟
You're asking me why?
تسألني لماذا؟
Is there supposed to be a reason?
هل من المفترض أن يكون هناك سبب؟
Yes.
نعم.
Why do you like me?
لماذا تحبني؟
When did you start liking me?
متى بدأت تحبني؟
Lady Liu.
السيدة ليو.
We grew up together.
لقد نشأنا معًا.
I've known since I was little that you would be my wife.
لقد عرفت منذ أن كنت صغيرا أنك ستكونين زوجتي.
What other reason do I need?
ما هو السبب الآخر الذي أحتاجه؟
We grew up together?
لقد نشأنا معا؟
Is this a painting…
هل هذه لوحة فنية؟
of your childhood friend?
من صديق طفولتك؟
So that's why I always thought something was missing from this room.
لهذا السبب كنت أعتقد دائمًا أن هناك شيئًا مفقودًا من هذه الغرفة.
It turns out this painting is with you.
اتضح أن هذه اللوحة معك.
The Liu Taizhen you first knew,
ليو تاي تشن الذي عرفته لأول مرة،
the Liu Taizhen you liked most,
Liu Taizhen الذي أعجبك أكثر،
and the Liu Taizhen you were engaged to,
وليو تاي تشن الذي كنت مخطوبة له،
were not me.
لم أكن أنا.
The Liu Taizhen you grew up with,
ليو تاي تشن الذي نشأت معه،
the Liu Taizhen who liked you,
ليو تاي تشن الذي أحبك،
actually died…
مات فعلا…
10 years ago.
منذ 10 سنوات.
Everyone knows that…
الجميع يعرف ذلك…
when the Liu family's daughter was young, she accidentally fell off a cliff
عندما كانت ابنة عائلة ليو صغيرة، سقطت عن طريق الخطأ من على منحدر
but survived the fall.
ولكنه نجا من السقوط.
But did no one think about it?
ولكن هل فكر أحد في هذا الأمر؟
For a mortal body…
من أجل جسد فانٍ…
to fall from a cliff…
السقوط من على جرف…
How could she possibly come back to life?
كيف يمكنها أن تعود إلى الحياة؟
As the Snake Lord of the Demon Underworld,
بصفته سيد الثعابين في عالم الشياطين السفلي،
I often had to travel in the Mortal Realm.
كان عليّ في كثير من الأحيان أن أسافر في عالم البشر.
My previous identity was no longer sustainable.
لم تعد هويتي السابقة قابلة للاستدامة.
So I borrowed her body.
لذلك استعرت جسدها.
When Liu Gongshen learned that his daughter was found,
عندما علم ليو جونجشين أنه تم العثور على ابنته،
he didn't know that though I looked like her,
لم يكن يعلم أنني على الرغم من أنني أشبهها،
everything had long since changed.
لقد تغير كل شيء منذ فترة طويلة.
But…
لكن…
But Wu Zhen is also a demon.
لكن وو تشن هو أيضًا شيطان.
But she's clearly Wu Zhen.
لكن من الواضح أنها وو تشن.
She's an anomaly.
إنها شاذة.
She became a demon in human form.
أصبحت شيطانًا في شكل إنسان.
So she's half-human, half-demon.
إذن فهي نصف إنسانة ونصف شيطانة.
As for me,
أما بالنسبة لي،
I am not.
انا لست كذلك.
It's you!
إنه أنت!
I thought it was Xiao Mu or Chi Hua.
اعتقدت أنه كان شياو مو أو تشي هوا.
What are you looking at?
ماذا تنظر اليه؟
I secretly took a few martial arts manuals.
لقد أخذت سراً بعض كتيبات الفنون القتالية.
I'm studying them now.
أنا أدرسهم الآن.
Soon,
قريباً،
I'll be both a demon and a cultivator.
سوف أكون شيطانًا ومزارعًا.
With my profound power,
بفضل قوتي العميقة،
I'll be the greatest demon in the world
سأكون أعظم شيطان في العالم
who travels between the Mortal Realm and the Demon Underworld.
الذي يسافر بين عالم البشر وعالم الشياطين السفلي.
What?
ماذا؟
I'm going to master all the practices
سأتقن جميع الممارسات
of Changxi Palace.
قصر تشانغشي.
Aren't you worried at all?
ألا تشعر بالقلق على الإطلاق؟
Learn all you want.
تعلم كل ما تريد.
You can ask me if there's something you don't understand.
يمكنك أن تسألني إذا كان هناك شيء لا تفهمه.
I'll teach you.
سأعلمك.
You underestimate me!
لقد قللت من شأني!
From its very essence,
من جوهرها،
Taoist magic and demonic magic are mutually exclusive.
السحر الطاوي والسحر الشيطاني متنافيان.
They cannot be merged.
لا يمكن دمجهم.
If you manage to master them,
إذا تمكنت من إتقانهم،
you'd be the most powerful being in existence.
سوف تكون أقوى كائن في الوجود.
I'm Cat Lord of Chang'an, mind you.
أنا سيد القطط في تشانغآن، انتبه لذلك.
Perhaps I'm the rarest genius
ربما أنا العبقري الأندر
this world has ever seen.
لم يشاهد هذا العالم مثله من قبل.
You…
أنت…
You are not her.
أنت لست هي.
You're not.
أنت لست.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I shouldn't have kept it a secret for so long.
لا ينبغي لي أن أبقي الأمر سرًا لفترة طويلة.
But I thought…
ولكنني اعتقدت...
mortals' emotions are fleeting.
إن عواطف البشر عابرة.
I thought if I ignored you,
اعتقدت أنه إذا تجاهلتك،
you would fall for someone else in no time.
سوف تقع في حب شخص آخر في أي وقت من الأوقات.
- I thought-- - You "thought"?
- لقد فكرت-- - هل "فكرت"؟
How can demons…
كيف يمكن للشياطين...
understand humans?
فهم البشر؟
Who are you to judge humans?
من أنت حتى تحكم على البشر؟
No wonder.
لا عجب.
Lady Liu's personality changed 10 years ago.
لقد تغيرت شخصية السيدة ليو منذ 10 سنوات.
She suddenly ignored me.
لقد تجاهلتني فجأة.
I thought it was my fault.
اعتقدت أنه كان خطئي.
I wondered what I did wrong.
لقد تساءلت عما فعلته خطأ.
But I never imagined…
ولكنني لم أتخيل ذلك أبدًا...
that you're not her.
أنك لست هي.
Give me back my Lady Liu!
أعيدوا لي سيدتي ليو!
Take your time to read and learn.
خذ وقتك للقراءة والتعلم.
What? Did you get your answer?
ماذا؟ هل حصلت على إجابتك؟
Or were you scolded?
أم أنك تعرضت للتوبيخ؟
You should be used to it by now.
ينبغي أن تكون معتادًا على ذلك الآن.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Let's not talk about you two.
دعونا لا نتحدث عنكما.
I'm here today
انا هنا اليوم
to tell you some good news.
لأخبرك ببعض الأخبار الجيدة.
- I-- - I want to be alone.
- أنا-- أريد أن أكون وحدي.
Chang'an's Yinglong.
تشانغآن ينجلونج.
Are you here for your tribulation to ascend?
هل أنت هنا لتصعد محنتك ؟
Yes.
نعم.
For a Yinglong to ascend,
لكي يصعد ينجلونج،
you must undergo this trial.
يجب عليك الخضوع لهذه المحاكمة.
If you're ready,
إذا كنت مستعدًا،
we shall begin.
سوف نبدأ.
I'm ready. I'm ready!
أنا مستعد. أنا مستعد!
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Why didn't I transform into a dragon?
لماذا لم أتحول إلى تنين؟
It's because you failed to ascend.
لأنك فشلت في الصعود.
You did grow dragon scales,
لقد قمت بزراعة قشور التنين،
but your heart is still troubled by worldly matters.
ولكن قلبك لا يزال مضطربًا بأمور الدنيا.
There are things that you must let go of
هناك أشياء يجب عليك أن تتخلى عنها
before you can ascend and transform into a dragon.
قبل أن تتمكن من الصعود والتحول إلى تنين.
Have a bite.
خذ قضمة.
You mortal.
أيها البشر.
Do I look vegetarian to you?
هل أبدو لك نباتيًا؟
I bet you're scared.
أعتقد أنك خائف.
You lowly mortal, why aren't you kneeling and bowing at the sight of me?
أيها الإنسان البسيط، لماذا لا تركع وتنحني عند رؤيتي؟
It was fine when you were obsessed with painting.
لقد كان الأمر جيدًا عندما كنت مهووسًا بالرسم.
But now,
ولكن الآن،
you've ended up with nothing but idle amusements.
لقد انتهيت إلى لا شيء سوى التسلية الفارغة.
You're keeping loaches now!
أنت تحتفظ باللويشات الآن!
Father.
أب.
It's not a loach.
إنه ليس سمكة لوتش.
Little Loach, I'll protect you. Hide well in my arms.
يا ليتل لوتش، سأحميك. اختبئ جيدًا بين ذراعيّ.
Didn't you ask for this marriage?
ألم تطلب هذا الزواج؟
You think you get to marry her if you want to
تعتقد أنك تستطيع الزواج منها إذا كنت تريد ذلك
and back out when you don't?
وتتراجع عندما لا تفعل ذلك؟
That's right. I've changed my mind.
هذا صحيح. لقد غيرت رأيي.
I don't want to do it.
لا أريد أن أفعل ذلك.
I'm not marrying Lady Liu.
أنا لا أتزوج السيدة ليو.
Why did you reject the marriage?
لماذا رفضت الزواج؟
My tarnishing a woman's virtue and being irresponsible
تشويهي لفضيلة المرأة وعدم مسؤوليتي
would still be better than putting Lady Liu in a tough spot.
لا يزال من الأفضل أن تفعل ذلك بدلاً من وضع السيدة ليو في موقف صعب.
In ordinary matters,
في الأمور العادية،
it's fine to go along with the ways of the world.
لا بأس من مواكبة طرق العالم.
But marriage is a serious matter.
لكن الزواج أمر خطير.
How can she be bound by the rules of mortals again?
كيف يمكنها أن تكون مقيدة بقواعد البشر مرة أخرى؟
So to him,
لذلك بالنسبة له،
we demons
نحن الشياطين
shouldn't be besieged by the masses.
لا ينبغي أن تحاصرها الجماهير.
Instead, we should be free
بدلا من ذلك، ينبغي لنا أن نكون أحرارا
and unrestrained.
وغير مقيد.
It's all those two's fault.
إنه خطأ هؤلاء الإثنان.
They ruined my plan.
لقد خربوا خطتي.
Don't go! Don't go!
لا تذهب! لا تذهب!
I haven't become a dragon yet!
لم أصبح تنينًا بعد!
Don't go!
لا تذهب!
Heaven and Earth as one
السماء والأرض كواحد
Lady Wu.
السيدة وو.
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
Fifth Brother.
الأخ الخامس.
There's something I'd like your help with.
هناك شيء أريد مساعدتك فيه.
Just say it.
فقط قلها.
Heaven and Earth as one
السماء والأرض كواحد
Help!
يساعد!
- Help! - Fifth Brother!
- النجدة! - الأخ الخامس!
- What's wrong, Fifth Brother?
- ما الأمر يا أخي الخامس؟ - يا أخي الخامس!
Don't come near me!
لا تقترب مني!
Fifth Brother, are you being serious?
الأخ الخامس هل أنت جاد؟
This is unacceptable!
هذا أمر غير مقبول!
It's just an arm.
إنه مجرد ذراع.
Everyone in Changxi Palace
الجميع في قصر تشانغشي
is naked on top during morning training.
يظهر عارياً من الأعلى أثناء التدريب الصباحي.
I've seen it all.
لقد رأيت كل شيء.
That's not the same! Men and women should not be intimate.
هذا ليس صحيحًا! لا ينبغي للرجال والنساء أن يكونوا على علاقة حميمة.
If I treat you, I'll have to touch you.
إذا قمت بعلاجك، فسوف أضطر إلى لمسك.
That goes against propriety. Moreover, you are a married woman.
هذا يتنافى مع الآداب العامة. علاوة على ذلك، أنتِ امرأة متزوجة.
With your husband by your side,
مع زوجك بجانبك
if I were to show you disrespect, it would show a lack of etiquette.
إذا أظهرت لك عدم الاحترام، فسيكون ذلك بمثابة افتقار إلى الآداب.
Baring oneself in the name of martial practice is justifiable.
إن كشف الذات باسم التدريب العسكري أمر مبرر.
How can a lady behave so recklessly?
كيف يمكن للسيدة أن تتصرف بتهور هكذا؟
It's highly improper. Highly improper!
هذا غير لائق تمامًا. غير لائق تمامًا!
I am a martial artist.
أنا فنان عسكري.
I absolutely cannot do that!
لا أستطيع فعل ذلك على الإطلاق!
You…
أنت…
Fifth Brother. You're quite eloquent, aren't you?
الأخ الخامس. أنت فصيحٌ جدًا، أليس كذلك؟
Fifth Brother, is that really you?
الأخ الخامس، هل هذا أنت حقًا؟
Fifth Brother, are you sure you're yourself?
الأخ الخامس هل أنت متأكد من نفسك؟
Fifth Brother!
الأخ الخامس!
You're not possessed by a demon, are you?
أنت لست ممسوسًا بالشيطان، أليس كذلك؟
Fifth Brother, what's wrong? Are you all right?
أخي الخامس، ما بك؟ هل أنت بخير؟
Fifth Brother, are you all right?
الأخ الخامس هل أنت بخير؟
Fifth Brother, do you feel unwell anywhere?
الأخ الخامس هل تشعر بتوعك في أي مكان؟
What's wrong? Tell us!
ما المشكلة؟ أخبرنا!
Help me!
ساعدني!
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
What's wrong? Do you feel unwell?
ما بك؟ هل تشعر بتوعك؟
I saw something strange growing on my arm.
رأيت شيئًا غريبًا ينمو على ذراعي.
I came to get it treated.
لقد جئت للحصول على العلاج.
Show me.
أرِنِي.
Yuzhen Pavilion
جناح يوجين
This is the first time I've seen you like this.
هذه هي المرة الأولى التي أراك فيها هكذا.
You've truly lived for centuries in vain.
لقد عشت حقا قرونا من الزمن عبثا.
Did you just grow older without growing wiser?
هل كبرت للتو دون أن تصبح أكثر حكمة؟
So what if you didn't tell him about it?
فماذا لو لم تخبره بذلك؟
I can't hide it forever.
لا أستطيع إخفاء ذلك إلى الأبد.
There are things that, once you say them,
هناك أشياء، بمجرد أن تقولها،
you'll lose everything.
سوف تخسر كل شيء.
Wouldn't it be better to be happy for as long as possible?
أليس من الأفضل أن نكون سعداء لأطول فترة ممكنة؟
The incident with Little Kitty made me realize
لقد جعلني الحادث مع ليتل كيتي أدرك
some things are better explained sooner.
بعض الأشياء يمكن شرحها بشكل أفضل في وقت أقرب.
Lest you harm yourself and others.
لكي لا تؤذي نفسك والآخرين.
If you ask me,
إذا سألتني،
Mei Si is an idiot.
مي سي هو احمق.
Since he can accept that you're a demon,
لأنه يستطيع أن يتقبل أنك شيطان،
then why can't he
إذن لماذا لا يستطيع؟
accept the fact that you are not the original Liu Taizhen?
هل تقبل حقيقة أنك لست ليو تاي تشن الأصلي؟
Because what he loves isn't me,
لأنه ما يحبه ليس أنا،
but the memory of the past.
ولكن ذكرى الماضي.
You don't have to try to be matchmaker for us anymore.
لم يعد عليك أن تحاول التوفيق بيننا بعد الآن.
Just focus on cultivating and ascending.
فقط ركز على الزراعة والارتقاء.
Do you think I want to meddle in your affairs?
هل تعتقد أنني أريد التدخل في شؤونك؟
You two are the ones who are delaying my ascension to a dragon.
أنتما الاثنان من يؤخر صعودي إلى التنين.
How about I bring him here? You two can talk again.
ماذا لو أحضرته إلى هنا؟ يمكنكما التحدث مجددًا.
No need.
لا حاجة.
I was just about to capture you, but you're already here.
لقد كنت على وشك القبض عليك، ولكنك هنا بالفعل.
Hurry and talk things out with your Lady Liu.
اسرع وتحدث عن الأمور مع سيدتك ليو.
Hurry!
عجل!
Where is Lady Liu?
أين السيدة ليو؟
What?
ماذا؟
Lady Liu?
السيدة ليو؟
Where is my Liu Taizhen?
أين ليو تاي تشن؟
I'll take you there.
سوف آخذك إلى هناك.
Since I took her identity,
منذ أن أخذت هويتها،
I couldn't leave a name for her.
لم أستطع أن أترك لها اسمًا.
No one tended her grave after her passing.
لم يعتني أحد بقبرها بعد رحيلها.
I was the one who couldn't do right by her.
لقد كنت الشخص الذي لم يتمكن من فعل الصواب لها.
We've been apart for 10 years.
لقد كنا منفصلين لمدة 10 سنوات.
You used to love lively places.
كنت تحب الأماكن الحيوية.
You must be very lonely
يجب أن تكون وحيدًا جدًا
in this wilderness.
في هذه البرية.
Your wife…
زوجتك…
I can't save her.
لا أستطيع انقاذها.
What she has is not an illness,
ما لديها ليس مرضًا،
but her tribulation.
ولكن محنتها.
No can do!
لا أستطيع فعل ذلك!
Can you please not shout?
هل يمكنك من فضلك عدم الصراخ؟
It's a bit scary.
إنه أمر مخيف بعض الشيء.
I already made an exception when I let you into the archive.
لقد قمت بالفعل باستثناء عندما سمحت لك بالدخول إلى الأرشيف.
I can't always make exceptions on your account.
لا أستطيع دائمًا عمل استثناءات لحسابك.
Besides, this is too dangerous.
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، فهذا أمر خطير للغاية.
I'm not doing it.
انا لا افعل ذلك.
I know you mean well.
أعرف أنك تقصد الخير.
But her demonic sores are regrowing.
لكن قروحها الشيطانية تنمو من جديد.
She doesn't have much time left.
لم يتبق لها الكثير من الوقت.
No matter what that tribulation is, I must find out the truth.
مهما كانت طبيعة هذا المحنة، لا بد أن أكتشف الحقيقة.
So…
لذا…
this magical tool found in the archive
هذه الأداة السحرية الموجودة في الأرشيف
can take Zhuyu back 18 years
يمكن أن يعيد Zhuyu 18 عامًا إلى الوراء
to see what happened that night.
لرؤية ما حدث في تلك الليلة.
Yes.
نعم.
That's amazing.
هذا مدهش.
For a mortal to reverse time
لكي يعود الإنسان إلى الزمن
is a forbidden spell that goes against the law of nature.
هي تعويذة محظورة تتعارض مع قانون الطبيعة.
If anything goes wrong, not only can you not save her,
إذا حدث أي خطأ، فلن تتمكن من إنقاذها فحسب،
but you yourself
لكنك نفسك
will also die in the turbulence of time.
وسوف يموت أيضًا في اضطراب الزمن.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
But as a Celestial Master,
ولكن بصفتي سيدًا سماويًا،
I cannot just disregard the Demonic Infant.
لا أستطيع تجاهل الطفل الشيطاني.
As a son…
كإبن…
I cannot stand by and do nothing about my parents' murderer.
لا أستطيع أن أقف مكتوف الأيدي ولا أفعل شيئًا بشأن قاتل والدي.
As a…
كـ…
I cannot stand by and watch my enemy
لا أستطيع الوقوف مكتوف الأيدي ومشاهدة عدوي
in the body of the person I love,
في جسد الشخص الذي أحبه،
draining her life.
استنزاف حياتها.
I've made up my mind.
لقد اتخذت قراري.
I must do this.
يجب علي أن أفعل هذا.
Please grant my wish.
أرجو أن تحقق لي رغبتي.
Tell everyone to get ready.
اطلب من الجميع أن يستعدوا.
Understood.
مفهومة.
It's so ugly.
إنه قبيح جداً.
Are you sure it's from Changxi Palace?
هل أنت متأكد أنها من قصر تشانغشي؟
It's precisely because it's ugly that I'm sure.
إنه على وجه التحديد لأنه قبيح، وأنا متأكد من ذلك.
What does it say?
ماذا يقول؟
It says I need to go to Changxi Palace immediately.
يقول أنني بحاجة للذهاب إلى قصر تشانغشي على الفور.
Could there be progress regarding Cat Lord's matter?
هل يمكن أن يكون هناك تقدم فيما يتعلق بقضية سيد القطط؟
I hope so.
أتمنى ذلك.
I've been meaning to ask you something.
لقد كنت أريد أن أسألك شيئا.
Wu Zi Shu has been roaming the streets lately.
لقد كان وو زي شو يتجول في الشوارع في الآونة الأخيرة.
What exactly is he doing?
ماذا يفعل بالضبط؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
This was the place you wanted to go 18 years ago.
كان هذا هو المكان الذي أردت الذهاب إليه منذ 18 عامًا.
Take a look.
خذ نظرة.
Thank you so much, Mr. Ling Xiao.
شكرا جزيلا لك، السيد لينغ شياو.
You've helped me out of a tight spot.
لقد ساعدتني على الخروج من موقف صعب.
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Understood!
مفهوم!
Here, take it.
هنا، خذها.
Since the transaction is complete, I'll be on my way.
وبما أن المعاملة قد اكتملت، فسوف أكون في طريقي.
Why isn't the wine here yet?
لماذا لا يوجد النبيذ هنا حتى الآن؟
You still have guests…
لا زال لديك ضيوف...
at this hour?
في هذه الساعة؟
Guest?
ضيف؟
More like some lord.
أشبه ببعض اللوردات.
He's been drinking here for three days straight.
لقد كان يشرب هنا لمدة ثلاثة أيام متواصلة.
If he weren't rich, I would've chased him away a long ago.
لو لم يكن غنيًا، لكنت طردته منذ زمن طويل.
- A lord? - Mm.
- سيد؟ - مم.
What lord?
أي سيد؟
I heard a certain rich young lord has been drinking here for three days.
سمعت أن أحد اللوردات الأثرياء الشباب يشرب هنا منذ ثلاثة أيام.
Turns out it's you, Young Master Mei Si.
اتضح أنه أنت، السيد الشاب مي سي.
Mr. Ling Xiao.
السيد لينغ شياو.
How distant.
كم هي بعيدة.
Aren't you going to buy me a drink?
هل ستشتري لي مشروبًا؟
I don't have a cup.
ليس لدي كوب.
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
It seems I'm not welcome.
يبدو أنني غير مرحب بي.
After years of covering for you at Yuzhen Pavilion,
بعد سنوات من التغطية لك في جناح يوزين،
this so-called friendship only leaves me in sadness.
هذه الصداقة المزعومة لا تترك لي سوى الحزن.
Sadness?
حزن؟
Why are you here, Mr. Ling Xiao?
لماذا أنت هنا يا سيد لينغ شياو؟
Me?
أنا؟
I was just passing by.
لقد كنت أمر فقط.
I heard you were here,
سمعت أنك كنت هنا
so I came to tease you.
لذلك جئت لأضايقك.
Don't look at me like that.
لا تنظر إلي بهذه الطريقة.
I'm just concerned about you.
أنا فقط قلق عليك.
Why don't you go home?
لماذا لا تذهب إلى المنزل؟
Xuan Hui is there.
شوان هوي هناك.
So that "Grandpa" cornered you at your place,
حتى أن "الجد" حاصرك في مكانك،
and you're hiding here, drinking instead.
وأنت تختبئ هنا، وتشرب بدلاً من ذلك.
What do you mean, hiding?
ماذا تقصد بالاختباء؟
It's because this osmanthus wine is delicious.
لأن هذا النبيذ العطري لذيذ.
That's why I'm here.
لهذا السبب أنا هنا.
I'm not hiding.
أنا لا أختبئ.
Right.
يمين.
The osmanthus wine here is quite good.
النبيذ العثماني هنا جيد جدًا.
It's been popular in Chang'an for years.
لقد كانت مشهورة في تشانغآن لسنوات.
Many people have loved it as faithfully as on the first day.
لقد أحبها الكثير من الناس بإخلاص كما في اليوم الأول.
Just like…
تماما مثل…
your love for my master.
حبك لسيدي.
Mr. Ling Xiao, you can leave now.
السيد لينغ شياو، يمكنك المغادرة الآن.
All right.
حسنًا.
I don't want to be a nuisance here.
لا أريد أن أكون مصدر إزعاج هنا.
I just want to ask you one thing.
أريد فقط أن أسألك شيئا واحدا.
Everyone knows
الجميع يعرف
you've liked Lady Liu for over 10 years.
لقد أحببت السيدة ليو لأكثر من 10 سنوات.
But Lady Liu changed 10 years ago.
لكن السيدة ليو تغيرت منذ 10 سنوات.
Ten years,
عشر سنوات
and you still haven't come to understand her any better?
ومازلت لم تفهمها بشكل أفضل؟
Are your mind…
هل عقلك…
and your feelings
ومشاعرك
at a standstill,
في حالة توقف تام
still stuck at the beginning?
لا تزال عالقة في البداية؟
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
their wine is indeed delicious.
نبيذهم لذيذ حقا.
Because they use Chongyang osmanthus from the southwest.
لأنهم يستخدمون زهرة تشونغيانغ أوسمانثوس من الجنوب الغربي.
It's just a pity that some time ago,
إنه لأمر مؤسف أنه منذ بعض الوقت،
their carriage had an accident.
لقد تعرضت عربتهم لحادث.
Several carriages of Chongyang osmanthus were lost on the way.
لقد فقدت عدة عربات من أزهار تشونغيانغ أوسمانثوس في الطريق.
Therefore, they don't have any fresh osmanthus wine.
ولذلك، ليس لديهم أي نبيذ عثماني طازج.
But still, you want it urgently.
لكنك لا تزال تريد ذلك بشكل عاجل.
So…
لذا…
So it wasn't the osmanthus wine…
لذا لم يكن الأمر يتعلق بنبيذ أوسمانثوس...
that you said was delicious.
ما قلته كان لذيذًا.
I'm off.
انا ذاهب.
Seriously, if he can't figure it out himself,
بجدية، إذا لم يتمكن من معرفة ذلك بنفسه،
there's nothing anyone can do.
لا يوجد شيء يمكن لأي شخص فعله.
Don't you agree?
ألا توافق؟
Yes.
نعم.
Lord Shu.
اللورد شو.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
I'm just giving a heads-up.
أنا فقط أعطي تنبيهًا.
I'm taking these two demons with me.
سآخذ هذين الشيطانين معي.
My master said,
قال سيدي
since Cat Lord is coming back,
بما أن سيد القطط يعود،
I'll let you go first. I didn't have a choice back then.
سأدعك تذهب أولاً. لم يكن لدي خيار حينها.
Please don't blame…
من فضلك لا تلوم...
me.
أنا.
Is Snake Lord back?
هل عاد سيد الثعابين؟
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Do you have something to say to my master?
هل لديك شيئا لتقوله لسيدي؟
Not really.
ليس حقيقيًا.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Lord Shu, now that the ban has been lifted,
سيد شو، الآن وقد تم رفع الحظر،
you seem to be in high spirits.
يبدو أنك في حالة معنوية عالية.
Let's talk inside.
دعونا نتحدث في الداخل.
Do you have a plan, Lord Shu?
هل لديك خطة يا سيد شو؟
Lord Shu.
اللورد شو.
You haven't gotten the key to the door yet.
لم تحصل على مفتاح الباب بعد.
No need to gloat.
لا داعي للتفاخر.
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
Did you follow me?
هل تابعتني؟
Lord Shu.
اللورد شو.
Don't put it that way.
لا تضع الأمر بهذه الطريقة.
I saw you searching around the Demon Underworld two days ago.
لقد رأيتك تبحث في عالم الشياطين السفلي قبل يومين.
You were very focused.
لقد كنت مركزاً جداً.
I wasn't the only demon who paid attention to you.
لم أكن الشيطان الوحيد الذي اهتم بك.
You should thank me.
ينبغي عليك أن تشكرني.
If I didn't lead them away,
إذا لم أقودهم بعيدًا،
you wouldn't have found that place
لن تجد هذا المكان
so easily.
بسهولة.
It seems like…
يبدو أن…
I should thank you, Elder Hui.
يجب أن أشكرك، الشيخ هوي.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
I just want to collaborate with you, Lord Shu.
أريد فقط أن أتعاون معك، يا سيد شو.
I want to go in together.
أريد أن نذهب معًا.
As expected of the demon who had free rein in Chang'an
كما هو متوقع من الشيطان الذي كان له حرية التصرف في تشانغآن
all these years.
كل هذه السنوات.
You're truly resilient.
أنت مرن حقًا.
There's no other way.
لا يوجد طريقة أخرى.
You are Lord Infant's confidant after all.
أنت في نهاية المطاف صديق اللورد إنفانت المقرب.
If I want to go in and take a look,
إذا أردت أن أدخل وألقي نظرة،
I'll need your help, Lord Shu.
سأحتاج إلى مساعدتك، يا سيد شو.
Isn't that right?
أليس هذا صحيحا؟
That's the former grounds of the Demon Underworld.
هذه هي الأراضي السابقة لعالم الشياطين السفلي.
Only Snake Lord and Cat Lord can enter and exit as they wish.
فقط سيد الثعابين وسيد القطط يستطيعان الدخول والخروج كما يحلو لهما.
Currently, Snake Lord is the only one in Chang'an.
في الوقت الحالي، سيد الثعبان هو الوحيد في تشانغآن.
If we wish to enter,
إذا أردنا الدخول،
we will have to approach Snake Lord.
سيتعين علينا أن نتوجه إلى سيد الثعابين.
It seems that,
يبدو أن،
Lord Shu,
اللورد شو،
you need a helper.
تحتاج إلى مساعد.
Elder Hui, you're quite the silver tongue.
الشيخ هوي، أنت لسان فضي تماما.
I'm sure you've already thought of a way to get me the key.
أنا متأكد من أنك قد فكرت بالفعل في طريقة لإعطائي المفتاح.
Lord Shu.
اللورد شو.
You're trying to pry into Lord Infant's secret
أنت تحاول التطفل على سر اللورد الرضيع
to save Cat Lord, am I right?
لإنقاذ سيد القطط، هل أنا على حق؟
We can certainly collaborate.
يمكننا بالتأكيد أن نتعاون.
Once we find Lord Infant's secret,
بمجرد أن نجد سر اللورد الرضيع،
we won't interfere with each other…
لن نتدخل مع بعضنا البعض
nor get in each other's way.
ولا يقفوا في طريق بعضهم البعض.
All right.
حسنًا.
Eighteen years…
ثمانية عشر عاما…
The core has been in her body for 18 years.
لقد كان النواة في جسدها لمدة 18 عامًا.
Strange signs have been showing up frequently.
وقد ظهرت علامات غريبة بشكل متكرر.
I'm afraid it can no longer be sealed.
أخشى أنه لم يعد من الممكن إغلاقه.
I need to see the moment the previous Cat Lord sealed it.
أريد أن أرى اللحظة التي ختمها فيها سيد القطط السابق.
Only then can I find a solution and keep her safe.
حينها فقط يمكنني إيجاد الحل والحفاظ على سلامتها.
Thank you, everyone.
شكرا للجميع.
Zhuyu, remember this.
تشويو، تذكر هذا.
This act itself goes against the laws of nature.
إن هذا الفعل في حد ذاته يتعارض مع قوانين الطبيعة.
When you return to the past,
عندما تعود إلى الماضي،
you must not alter cause and effect, or change life and death.
لا يجوز لك تغيير السبب والنتيجة، أو تغيير الحياة والموت.
I understand.
أفهم.
Let's begin.
لنبدأ.
Heaven and Earth as one
السماء والأرض كواحد
Everything that has happened is predestined.
كل ما حدث هو مقدر.
If you act rashly,
إذا تصرفت بتهور،
not only will you be trapped between the past and present forever,
لن تظل عالقًا بين الماضي والحاضر إلى الأبد فحسب،
but the world itself
لكن العالم نفسه
may change in ways no one can foresee.
قد تتغير الأمور بطرق لا يستطيع أحد التنبؤ بها.
Mei Teahouse
بيت شاي مايو
Translated by Scarlet
ترجمتها سكارليت